<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Breakthesiege on indymedia.pt</title>
    <link>https://blog.indymedia.pt/tags/breakthesiege/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Breakthesiege on indymedia.pt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>pt-pt</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:36:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.indymedia.pt/tags/breakthesiege/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>9 embarcações da Global Sumud Flotilla aproximam-se de Gaza com 150 pessoas a bordo entre muitos jornalistas e médicos</title>
      <link>https://blog.indymedia.pt/?p=227965/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.indymedia.pt/?p=227965/</guid>
      <description>WE’LL NEVER STOP: 9 More Ships Now 140 Nautical Miles from Gaza.&#xA;The mission continues! Despite the illegal abduction of the Global Sumud Flotilla crew, a powerful new fleet is now critically close to the shores of Gaza.&#xA;This collaborative fleet, a union of the Freedom Flotilla Coalition (@gazafreedomflotilla) and Thousand Madleens to Gaza (@thousandmadleenstogaza), is sailing with nearly 150 people from 30 countries. They are just 140 nautical miles from Gaza right now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sumud Flotilla: 500 pessoas raptadas de 40 barcos perto costa de Gaza, protestos  em todo o mundo</title>
      <link>https://blog.indymedia.pt/news/2025-10-01-gaza-sumud-flotilla-em-alerta-vermelho-enfrenta-bloqueio-naval/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.indymedia.pt/news/2025-10-01-gaza-sumud-flotilla-em-alerta-vermelho-enfrenta-bloqueio-naval/</guid>
      <description>BREAKING: Israeli forces seize control of over 40 ships in the Sumud Flotilla. &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; 40 BOATS OF THE &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://x.com/hashtag/GlobalSumudFlotilla?src=hashtag_click&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#GlobalSumudFlotilla&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; HAVE NOW BEEN SEIZED. ONLY 12 REMAIN AND ARE SPEEDING TOWARDS &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://x.com/hashtag/GAZA?src=hashtag_click&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#GAZA&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; AT TOP SPEED WITH ISRAELI MILITARY VESSELS BEHIND THEM IN THE DISTANCE!!!! &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; Mikeno ship successfully broke through the Israeli blockade and entered Gaza&amp;amp;#8217;s territorial waters!! &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; SOME &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://x.com/hashtag/GlobalSumudFlotilla?src=hashtag_click&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#GlobalSumudFlotilla&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; SHIPS ARE AROUND 8-7 KILOMETERS FROM &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://x.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Todos os olhos no Hospital al-Shifa: último hopital funcional em Gaza parcialmente evacuado e em ruínas; Sumud Flotilla atacada por drones</title>
      <link>https://blog.indymedia.pt/?p=226565/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 03:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.indymedia.pt/?p=226565/</guid>
      <description>No medicine, no beds, no food or water: inside Gaza City’s main hospital As the Israeli invasion of Gaza City advances, al-Shifa Hospital is facing severe shortages of essential medical supplies, leaving patients untreated and vulnerable. Staff and patients fear an imminent Israeli attack.&#xA;https://mondoweiss.net/2025/09/no-medicine-no-beds-no-food-or-water-inside-gaza-citys-main-hospital/&#xA;A view of al-Shifa Hospital, left empty after medical staff and patients were forced to evacuate due to intensified Israeli attacks in Gaza City, Gaza, on September 25, 2025.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🇵🇸 Barco Madleen da Freedom Flotilla vai partir hoje com apoio humanitário para quebrar o bloqueio a Gaza 🇵🇸 Call to action today 🔻</title>
      <link>https://blog.indymedia.pt/?p=225485/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 11:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.indymedia.pt/?p=225485/</guid>
      <description>‘Madleen’ sails to Gaza today with twelve humanitarians and as much life-saving aid as she can carry, including baby formula, medical supplies, and more. She departs from European territorial waters, sailing entirely through international waters into Palestinian waters off Gaza.&#xA;Unarmed and nonviolent, ‘Madleen’ poses no threat. She sails in full accordance with international law. Any attack or interference will be a deliberate, unlawful assault on civilians.&#xA;That’s why @lanzybear @susansarandon @fababs @brianeno @maxmaxporter @aiysha_hart @gretathunberg @liamcunningham1 @indyamoore @zein_rahma @betteblavatsky @melissabarreram @lisamoorish @nicolejenes @realjulietstevenson @misanharriman @khalid3bdalla @nangoldinstudio @susanabulhawa @robert3delnaja @leavecaricealone and more have joined in support.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
